<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-04T13:04:19-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Li-Fang Cheng</title><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/undergoing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2018-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-05-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/undergoing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/undergoing/"></content><author><name>Li-Fang</name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/profile.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">MedGP: Sparse Multi-Output Gaussian Processes for Medical Time Series Prediction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/medgp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MedGP: Sparse Multi-Output Gaussian Processes for Medical Time Series Prediction" /><published>2017-03-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-03-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/medgp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/medgp/">&lt;p&gt;In the scenario of real-time monitoring of hospital patients, high-quality inference of patients’ health status using all information available from clinical covariates and lab tests is essential to enable successful medical interventions and improve patient outcomes. Developing a computational framework that can learn from observational large-scale electronic health records (EHRs) and make accurate real-time predictions is a critical step to achieve this goal. However, existing medical time series data from EHRs pose several challenges for conventional methods. For instance, many of the covariates, lab results in particular, are sparsely sampled in time across patients. In addition, there are substantial uncertainties in patient state and disease progression at any time. These properties make inferring the physiological status of a patient or joint analysis of time series across patients challenging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this work, we introduce MedGP, a statistical framework that leverages observational noisy medical time series data to enable personalized, real-time predictions of patient states and improve the clinical decision-making process. MedGP is based on multi-output Gaussian processes (MOGPs), a Bayesian nonparametric model that can capture rich temporal structures between clinical covariates from heterogeneous and irregularly sampled time series data. First, we show the design of highly structured and regularized kernel for robust estimation of the correlations among clinical covariates. We then show ways to efficiently implement the proposed approach and relieve the computational bottleneck imposed by learning GP parameters across many patients. The empirical results of MedGP show statistically significant improvements over baselines in making online predictions on multiple disease cohorts from two real-world medical datasets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details of the project can be found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://arxiv.org/abs/1703.09112&quot;&gt;our arXiv paper&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Li-Fang</name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html">In the scenario of real-time monitoring of hospital patients, high-quality inference of patients’ health status using all information available from clinical covariates and lab tests is essential to enable successful medical interventions and improve patient outcomes. Developing a computational framework that can learn from observational large-scale electronic health records (EHRs) and make accurate real-time predictions is a critical step to achieve this goal. However, existing medical time series data from EHRs pose several challenges for conventional methods. For instance, many of the covariates, lab results in particular, are sparsely sampled in time across patients. In addition, there are substantial uncertainties in patient state and disease progression at any time. These properties make inferring the physiological status of a patient or joint analysis of time series across patients challenging.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Temporal-Difference Approach with Unsupervised Data Imputation for Early Sepsis Prediction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sepsis_prediction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Temporal-Difference Approach with Unsupervised Data Imputation for Early Sepsis Prediction" /><published>2013-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2013-12-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sepsis_prediction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sepsis_prediction/">&lt;p&gt;Sepsis is one of the leading causes of death in critically ill patients. Each year an estimated 750,000 cases of sepsis or septic shock occur in the United States. The mortality rate of septic patients ranges from 20% to 30%, and accounts for roughly 9.3% of all US deaths. It is challenging to accurately diagnose sepsis onset due to heterogeneous symptoms across patients. For instance, conventional systemic inflammatory response syndrome (SIRS) criteria are widely adopted by physicians, but the specificity is suggested to be as low as 35% in some clinical studies. Therefore, more powerful biomarkers as well as prediction algorithms are needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this work, we aim at predicting sepsis through training a model on historical physiological time series data from Electronic Health Records (EHRs). There are two major challenges. The first one is to handle the incomplete physiological time series data due to the difference in ordering frequency between different clinical measurements. Second, features with higher predictive power should be developed. We first explore and compare serveral unsupervised clustering algorithms for imputing missing values. Next, we propose to extract temporal-difference features based on the imputed data and train a support vector machine (SVM) to identify the states before clinically annotated onsets. The empirical results show that our approach outperforms clinical baselines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was presented by poster at the &lt;em&gt;Machine Learning for Clinical Data Analysis, Healthcare and Genomics Workshop, Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS), 2014&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Li-Fang</name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html">Sepsis is one of the leading causes of death in critically ill patients. Each year an estimated 750,000 cases of sepsis or septic shock occur in the United States. The mortality rate of septic patients ranges from 20% to 30%, and accounts for roughly 9.3% of all US deaths. It is challenging to accurately diagnose sepsis onset due to heterogeneous symptoms across patients. For instance, conventional systemic inflammatory response syndrome (SIRS) criteria are widely adopted by physicians, but the specificity is suggested to be as low as 35% in some clinical studies. Therefore, more powerful biomarkers as well as prediction algorithms are needed.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Side Project1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/side/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Side Project1" /><published>2013-07-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-07-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/side</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/side/">&lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Li-Fang</name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html">…</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/profile.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Master Thesis: Algorithm and System Design for Prevention of Sudden Cardiac Death</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Master Thesis: Algorithm and System Design for Prevention of Sudden Cardiac Death" /><published>2013-07-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-07-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/master_thesis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/master_thesis/">&lt;p&gt;Sudden Cardiac Death (SCD) is one of the leading causes of death in current society. Although increasing efforts have been done in clinical care, the survival rate of SCD remains low. To improve patient outcomes as well as actively prevent SCD, we aim at designing an energy-efficient intelligent system that can predict the cardiac health status and provide real-time warnings for users outside of hospitals. We achieve this by first developing features based on time-frequency scalogram extracted from ECG and then training a support vector machine (SVM) for classification of adverse pre-SCD events. The positive predictive value is reported to be over 95% on the standard MIT-BIH dataset. We also design and implement a versatile ECG processor with high functional flexibility and low power consumption to meet the requirements of an ideal real-time SCD prevention system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was developed during my master study at Graduate Institute of Electronics Engineering, National Taiwan University (NTU), advised by Prof. &lt;a href=&quot;http://video.ee.ntu.edu.tw/~lgchen/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Liang-Gee Chen&lt;/a&gt;. The thesis can be accessed through &lt;a href=&quot;http://dx.doi.org/10.6342/NTU.2013.00511&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;DOI:10.6342/NTU.2013.00511&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Li-Fang</name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html">Sudden Cardiac Death (SCD) is one of the leading causes of death in current society. Although increasing efforts have been done in clinical care, the survival rate of SCD remains low. To improve patient outcomes as well as actively prevent SCD, we aim at designing an energy-efficient intelligent system that can predict the cardiac health status and provide real-time warnings for users outside of hospitals. We achieve this by first developing features based on time-frequency scalogram extracted from ECG and then training a support vector machine (SVM) for classification of adverse pre-SCD events. The positive predictive value is reported to be over 95% on the standard MIT-BIH dataset. We also design and implement a versatile ECG processor with high functional flexibility and low power consumption to meet the requirements of an ideal real-time SCD prevention system.</summary></entry></feed>